[
    {
        "question": "Ic (<em>habban</em>) #### ðe to secgenne sum þing⁠ — I have something to say",
        "correctAnswer": "hæbbe",
        "explanation": "Here 'habban' is in the first person singular form '<em>hæbbe</em>' because the subject is 'I'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðu (<em>libban</em>) #### be godra manna ælmessan⁠ — You live by alms of good men",
        "correctAnswer": "leofast",
        "explanation": "Here 'libban' is in the second person singular form '<em>leofast</em>' because the subject is 'You",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Swa (<em>secgan</em>) #### ðæs huses hlaforde⁠ — The lord of this house says so",
        "correctAnswer": "secgað|secgaþ",
        "explanation": "Here 'secgan' is in the third person singular form '<em>secgað</em>' because the subject is 'the lord'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "(<em>hycgan</em>) #### his ealle hu ge hie beswicen⁠ — All think of this, how you may deceive them",
        "correctAnswer": "hycgaþ|hycgað;",
        "explanation": "Here 'hycgan' is in the plural form '<em>hycgað</em>' because the subject is 'all'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðis leoht we (<em>habban</em>) #### wið nytenu gemæne⁠ — This light we have in common with beasts",
        "correctAnswer": "habbaþ|habbað",
        "explanation": "Here 'habban' is in the plural form '<em>habbað</em>' because the subject is 'We'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie be urum larum (<em>libban</em>) ####⁠ — They live according to our instructions",
        "correctAnswer": "libbaþ|libbað",
        "explanation": "Here 'libban' is in the plural form '<em>libbað</em>' because the subject is 'They'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic ðe orlæg (<em>secgan</em>) ####⁠ — I told thee thy fate",
        "correctAnswer": "secgde ",
        "explanation": "Here 'secgan' is in the first person singular form '<em>secgde</em>' because the subject is 'I",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðu (<em>hycgan</em>) #### on ellen ac wærwyrde sceal wisfæst hæle breostum hycgan⁠ — You thought on valour, but a wise and cautious man holds his thoughts to his breast",
        "correctAnswer": "hogdest",
        "explanation": "Here 'hycgan' is in the second person singular past form '<em>hogdest</em>' because the subject is 'You'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Her (<em>habban</em>) #### se cyning his hired æt Gleaweceastre⁠ — On this year, the king had his court at Gloucester",
        "correctAnswer": "hæfde",
        "explanation": "Here 'habban' is in the third person singular past form '<em>hæfde</em>' because the subject is 'the king'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "hafde",
                "explanation": "Close, but remember, 'habban' takes an 'æ' instead of an 'a' in all past tense conjugations"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "We ealne ðysne gear (<em>libban</em>) #### mid ures lichoman willan⁠ — we have lived all this year as it was pleasing to our body",
        "correctAnswer": "lifdon",
        "explanation": "Here 'libban' is in the plural form '<em>lifdon</em>' because the subject is 'We'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ge guilty synne (<em>secgan</em>) ####⁠ — You the guilty spoke sin",
        "correctAnswer": "sægdon",
        "explanation": "Here 'secgan' is in the plural past form '<em>sægdon</em>' because the subject is the plural 'You'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie (<em>hycgan</em>) #### inwit and facen on heortan geþoncum⁠ — They thought deceit and treachery with the thoughts of their heart",
        "correctAnswer": "hogdon",
        "explanation": "Here 'hycgan' is in the third person singular past form '<em>hogdon</em>' because the subject is 'They'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "",
                "explanation": ""
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic bi me (<em>secgan</em>) #### ðis sarspell⁠ — I tell this lament about myself",
        "correctAnswer": "secge",
        "explanation": "Here 'secgan' is in the first person singular form '<em>secge</em>' because the subject is 'I'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Æðelwulf his dohtor (<em>habban</em>) #### him to cuene⁠ — Ethelwulf had his daughter for his queen",
        "correctAnswer": "hæfde",
        "explanation": "Here 'habban' is in the third person singular form '<em>hæfde</em>' because the subject is 'Ethelwulf'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie (<em>habban</em>) #### hine mid heom oþ ðet hie ofslogon hine⁠ — They had him with them until they slew him",
        "correctAnswer": "hæfdon",
        "explanation": "Here 'habban' is in the plural form '<em>hæfdon</em>' because the subject is 'They'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "",
                "explanation": ""
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "For ðam ic lybbe and ge (<em>libban</em>) ####⁠ — Because I live, you live",
        "correctAnswer": "libbaþ|libbað",
        "explanation": "Here 'libban' is in the plural form '<em>libbað</em>' because the subject is the plural 'You'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "",
                "explanation": ""
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Wynnum ond þeawum ic (<em>libban</em>) ####⁠ — I lived joyously and virutously",
        "correctAnswer": "lifde",
        "explanation": "Here 'libban' is in the first person past singular form '<em>lifde</em>' because the subject is 'I'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "",
                "explanation": ""
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Heo (<em>hycgan</em>) #### georne ðæt hire mægþhad clæne geheolde⁠ — She earnestly intended to keep her maidenhood pure",
        "correctAnswer": "hogde",
        "explanation": "Here 'hycgan' is in the third person singular past form '<em>hogde</em>' because the subject is 'She'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "",
                "explanation": ""
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ge (<em>habban</em>) #### us gedon laðe Pharaone⁠ — You have made us hateful to Pharoh",
        "correctAnswer": "habbaþ|habbað",
        "explanation": "Here 'habban' is in the plural form '<em>habbað</em>' because the subject is the plural 'You",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "",
                "explanation": ""
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðu me forlæred (<em>habban</em>) ####⁠ — You have seduced me",
        "correctAnswer": "hæfst",
        "explanation": "Here 'habban' is in the third person singular form '<em>hæfst</em>' because the subject is 'You'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "hæbbast|habbast|habast|hæbast|habst|hæbst",
                "explanation": "Remember, the 'b' in 'habban' becomes an 'f' in the 2nd and 3rd singular present, and all past tense conjugations"
            }
        ]
    }
]
